[
    {
        "numb": 1,
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to add the header file in the C++ program?",
        "answer": "Both A and B",
        "options": [
            "#include<userdefined>",
            "#include userdefined.h",
            "<include> userdefined.h",
            "Both A and B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 2,
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct identifier?",
        "answer": "VAR_123",
        "options": [
            "$var_name",
            "VAR_123",
            "varname@",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 3,
        "question": "Which of the following is the address operator?",
        "answer": "&",
        "options": [
            "@",
            "#",
            "&",
            "%"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 4,
        "question": "Which of the following features must be supported by any programming language to become a pure object-oriented programming language?",
        "answer": "All of the above",
        "options": [
            "Encapsulation",
            "Inheritance",
            "Polymorphism",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 5,
        "question": "The programming language that has the ability to create new data types is called___.",
        "answer": "Extensible",
        "options": [
            "Overloaded",
            "Extensible",
            "Reprehensible",
            "Encapsulated"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 6,
        "question": "Which of the following is the original creator of the C++ language?",
        "answer": "Bjarne Stroustrup",
        "options": [
            "Dennis Ritchie",
            "Ken Thompson",
            "Bjarne Stroustrup",
            "Brian Kernighan"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 7,
        "question": "The C++ language is ______ object-oriented language.",
        "answer": "Semi Object-oriented or Partial Object-oriented",
        "options": [
            "Pure Object oriented",
            "Semi Object-oriented or Partial Object-oriented",
            "None of the above",
            "Not Object oriented"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 8,
        "question": "Which of the following comment syntax is correct to create a single-line comment in the C++ program?",
        "answer": "//Comment",
        "options": [
            "//Comment",
            "/Comment/",
            "Comment//",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 9,
        "question": "C++ is a ___ type of language.",
        "answer": "Middle-level language",
        "options": [
            "High-level Language",
            "Low-level language",
            "Middle-level language",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 10,
        "question": "For inserting a new line in C++ program, which one of the following statements can be used?",
        "answer": "\n",
        "options": [
            "\n",
            "\r",
            "(a+b)",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 11,
        "question": "Which one of the following represents the tab?",
        "answer": "\t",
        "options": [
            "\n",
            "\t",
            "\r",
            "None of the above "
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 12,
        "question": " Which of the following refers to characteristics of an array?",
        "answer": "An array is a set of similar data items",
        "options": [
            "An array is a set of similar data items",
            "An array is a set of distinct data items",
            "An array can hold different types of datatypes",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 13,
        "question": "If we stored five elements or data items in an array, what will be the index address or the index number of the array's last data item?",
        "answer": "4",
        "options": [
            "3",
            "5",
            "4",
            "88"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 14,
        "question": "Which of the following gives the 4th element of the array?",
        "answer": "Array[3];",
        "options": [
            "Array[0];",
            "Array[0];",
            "Array[3];",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 15,
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax for declaring the array?",
        "answer": "    ",
        "options": [
            "init array []",
            "int array [5];",
            "Array[5];",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 16,
        "question": " Which type of memory is used by an Array in C++ programming language?",
        "answer": "Contiguous",
        "options": [
            "Contiguous",
            "None-contiguous",
            "Both A and B",
            "Not mentioned"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 17,
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct definition of sorting?",
        "answer": "Sorting is a type of process in which the data or information is ordered into a specific order. Example increasing orders, decreasing.",
        "options": [
            "Sorting is a type of process in which the data or information is ordered into a specific order. Example increasing orders, decreasing.",
            "Sorting information or data only in increasing order",
            "Sorting is a type of process in which data elements are modified or manipulated",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 18,
        "question": "How many types of the array are there in the C++ programming language?",
        "answer": "In the C++ programming language, there are two types of arrays",
        "options": [
            "In the C++ programming language, there are three types of arrays",
            "In the C++ programming language, there are four types of arrays",
            "In the C++ programming language, there are two types of arrays",
            "Both A and B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 19,
        "question": "In C++, for what purpose the rank() is used?",
        "answer": "It returns the dimension of the specified array",
        "options": [
            "It returns the maximum number of elements that can be stored in the array",
            "None of the above",
            "It returns the dimension of the specified array",
            "It returns the size of each dimension"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 20,
        "question": "What did we call an array of the one-dimensional array?",
        "answer": "2D Array (or 2-Dimensional array)",
        "options": [
            "Single Dimensional array",
            "Multi-Dimensional array",
            "2D Array (or 2-Dimensional array)",
            "Both A and B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 21,
        "question": "Which types of arrays are always considered as linear arrays?",
        "answer": "Single-dimensional",
        "options": [
            "Single-dimensional",
            "Multi-dimensional",
            "Both A and B",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 22,
        "question": "Which of the following can be considered as the object of an array?",
        "answer": "Elements of the Array",
        "options": [
            "Index of an array",
            "Elements of the Array",
            "Functions of the Array",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 23,
        "question": "Which of the following can be considered as the members that can be inherited but not accessible in any class?",
        "answer": "Private",
        "options": [
            "Public",
            "Protected",
            "Private",
            "Both A and C"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 24,
        "question": "Which of the following can be used to create an abstract class in the C++ programming language",
        "answer": "By using the pure virtual function in the class",
        "options": [
            "By using the pure virtual function in the class",
            "By declaring a virtual function in the base class",
            "By declaring the virtual keyword afterward, the class Declaration",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 25,
        "question": "Which of the following statements is correct about the class?",
        "answer": "An object is an instance of its class",
        "options": [
            "An object is an instance of its class",
            "A class is an instance of its object",
            "An object is the instance of the data type of that class",
            "Both A and C"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 26,
        "question": "Which of the following statement is not true about C++?",
        "answer": "A structure can have the member functions",
        "options": [
            "Members of a class are public by default",
            "A class cannot have the private members",
            "A structure can have the member functions",
            "All of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 27,
        "question": "Which one of the following cannot be used with the virtual keyword?",
        "answer": "Constructor",
        "options": [
            "Destructor",
            "Constructor",
            "Member function",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 28,
        "question": "Which of the following is used for implementing the late binding?",
        "answer": "Virtual Functions",
        "options": [
            "Operator Functions",
            "Constant Functions",
            "Virtual Functions",
            "Both A and B"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 29,
        "question": " Which of the following statement is correct about the C++ programming language?",
        "answer": "In C++, both the Static and Dynamic type checking are allowed",
        "options": [
            "In C++, both the Static and Dynamic type checking are allowed",
            "In C++, member function are allowed to be of the type canst",
            "In C++, Dynamic checking is allowed",
            "None of the above"
        ]
    },
    {
        "numb": 30,
        "question": "Which type of approach is used by the C++ language?",
        "answer": "Bottom-up",
        "options": [
            "Right to left",
            "Left to right",
            "Top to bottom",
            "Bottom-up"
        ]
    }
]